Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course in exercise
number seven seven, we are asked to sort this stack using temporary stack.
We have solved this problem in their previous video using their recursion.
But here we are, going to use a temporary stack and see how to sort a stack.
So this is the method that we have created before, and this is that.
The sort that stagnant the sort of insert stack.
OK.
And this to me.
No, I will create a method called probably public static or we can make FOI.
It's not return, it returns stack type stack, because we are going to assert the stack and return
it back.
Stack sort.
Stack.
Using them, so I need to pass a stack of time stack.
And it is called input.
This is the input of the fact that we need to pass and we need to.
Sought this input stack, so I will create a stack called TAM equal to new.
-- stack.
OK.
And.
This would be getting this size of the stack, how to get it.
We get that input size, we get the same input size, the same input stack size because we are going
to reverse it.
Wife
input input stack is empty.
This is the stopping condition of the while.
So we are going to make these steps, first of all, bob out.
The first element, the first element and equal to the MP, equal to input dot bob are popping up this
element.
And the second step, while temporary stack is not empty and top of the stack is greater than the stamp.
So we need to enter another nested loop and we are checking here.
Check for
not empty and less than 10.
And double
stacked up
less than 10 while
them per stack.
Which we have created them.
Stack, let me make it here, the temps back in order not to be confused with temp integer temp stack,
though, is empty and temp stack
dot.
Peak.
We are comparing it with them greater than them, then what we are going to do is popping off from that
temporary stack and pushing it into the input stack.
So input here, let me put that description popping from the temporary stack and at the end, pushing
it through the input
stack.
OK, so input
input dot push, we call it the method to push again.
Temporary stack the top OK.
So we have Bush popping again, popping from temporary stack and pushing it into the inputs that she
goes, how the algorithm works.
And we push that temporary into temporary of the stack.
So the first step is pushing the temp
and into
temporary of stacked
temp stack the bush and we insert temp inside and then we return them the stack.
OK, let's run and see this method sort that the stack and here I need to use her the stack.
Or stack the sort, the stack using temp and divests stack.
The same thing, but I'm using the different methods.
I need to print it again, sir, the stack setting for three, four, six, eight, six, seven, four
and eighty six.
OK, so we are inserting the stack.
We are searching the stack using them.
We didn't, but we didn't insert.
We didn't see that result correctly.
There is a method missing coding system for like sorting the stack.
I was meant for them because I need.
Do make is a temporary stack here, stack them them stack equal to.
Because I need to sort the stack first sort of thing that sort of caused it to return, distort the
stack and it took into the parking meter and important so.
Or is that I've put here this tag that they need to sort out, as we have learned here and now you can
make sorted numbers are.
System sorting wine
temp stack does not equal or empty, so it is not empty.
Then what we need to do, we need to system, get out the door and then stack the pot.
Plus space between them, let's run and see.
And here we go.
We have.
Sorted the stack in decreasing order.
OK.
This is the stack.
Seven, 74, 86 and 44 sorting the stack have 86, 74 and 44.
This is in in a decreasing order.
OK.
It's very simple, but and we have reversed it, so I will come and do this and run again.
And here we go.
86, 74 and 44.
OK, so this is how we sort there.
Stack, in a reversing order and decreasing order using the iteration, and we have learned in the previous
video how to sort it stack using their recursion.
OK, so sort of stack using temporary stack in decreasing order.
OK.
We have solved exercise number 70.